

ALEXANDRA KORENKOVA

Address: Sofia, Bulgaria

Email: alex.korenkova@gmail.com

Phone: +359 87 644 77 07 Website: alexa-studio.online

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Significant experience with a technical background in the web development. Proficiency in HTML(5)/CSS(3), Photoshop/Sketch/Figma, WordPress/Drupal, develop a responsive design using appropriated techniques, frameworks like React/Vue.js/Next.js, Node.js, SSR, preprocessing platform SASS/LESS, Gulp/Grunt for work automation, use principles and practices for optimizing layout, UI, cross-browser compatibility, accessibility, asynchronously request data with Ajax, version control system Git/GitHub/GitLab.

HIGHLIGHT

- Proficient in HTML(5)/CSS(3), Photoshop/Sketch/Figma, Gulp/Grunt, Node.js, Next.js, React/Redux, Vue.js, Bootstrap, Susy, Sass/Less, JavaScript/jQuery, WordPress/Drupal, Drupal tools such as Drush, Composer, Configuration Management, PHP/Twig, MySQL, Vagrant, VM Virtual Box, Git/GitHub, BrowserStack
- Project Scheduling
- Scrum/Agile development Jira/GitLab
- Exceptional Verbal and Written
 Communication Skill

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Career break for maternity leave

(2020 - 2023)

An extended period of maternity leave to bring up my daughter until she was old enough to start nursery school.

Valsoft Corporation | Montreal, Canada | valsoftcorp.com

(2020)

Front End Web Developer

- Building modern and responsive websites with WordPress.
- Development, configuration, migration, integration, testing and maintenance of WordPress websites.
- Collaborative working as part of a cross-functional team.

FFW Agency | Sofia, Bulgaria | ffwagency.com

(2018 - 2019)

Front End Developer

- Design and Develop Drupal themes and sub-themes.
- Writing PHP code to achieve the desired functionality in the Drupal theme.
- Building page layouts with content and blocks, building navigation with menus and toolbars, creating content types, and perform code reviews.
- Collaborative working as part of a cross-functional team through the development, configuration, migration, integration, testing, and maintenance of Drupal websites.
- Assistance in implementation and testing for new Drupal websites. Diagnosis and correction of any issues.
- Planning and implementation projects according to specifications, reporting of project statuses, identification of delays or resource shortages.

"ColourSite" Ltd. | Saint-Petersburg, Russia | coloursite.ru

(2010 - 2017)

Front End Developer, Project Manager

- Translating designs to front-end code, estimating time and costs, and determining developer requirements and specifications.
- Updating and streamlining existing code to improve site performance.
- Utilizing cutting edge JavaScript and HTML 5 techniques, frameworks, and libraries.
- Promoting and communication new ideas, process improvements, and new technologies to team members.
- Writing maintainable, scalable, responsive, and cross-browser code.
- Defining and controlling technical tasks according to schedule and budget.
- Coordination of actions of a development team.

EDUCATION

Saint-Petersburg State Forest Technical Academy, Russia BEng degree in Information systems and Technologies, 2006

SwiftAcademy, Bulgaria Front-End Course, 2018

LANGUAGES

Russian – native, English – proficiency, German – beginner, Bulgarian – conversational